/*
  Ges 101 .. 150 (Computer Appreciation)
  Ges 100 .. 74 (Communications in english)
  Ges 102
  Ges 103
  Ges 300 .. 130 (Enterprenurship)
 */

/* Communication in english */
final List<Map<String, dynamic>> ges100 = [
  {
    'id': 0,
    'question': 'Drawings of an area of the earth are referred to as',
    'answer': 'Maps',
    'options': 'Maps|Directives|Atlas|Handbooks',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 1,
    'question':
        'Books published yearly which carry information on various events for the coming year are called',
    'answer': 'Almanacs',
    'options': 'Year book|Annual book|Almanacs|Hand book',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 2,
    'question':
        'what holds the parts of the book together and makes them easy to handle',
    'answer': 'Binding',
    'options': 'Preliminary pages|Binding|Tight book|Surran tight',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 3,
    'question':
        'In which of the section of the library can we find the dictionary?',
    'answer': 'Reference',
    'options': 'Research section|Reference|Acquisition|None',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 4,
    'question':
        'The short description on the cover of a book is referred to as _______',
    'answer': 'Blurb',
    'options': 'Balb|Babule|Back print|Blurb',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 5,
    'question':
        'Never allow ______ days to elapse without making up the notes taken in class',
    'answer': 'Three',
    'options': 'Four|Two|Three|Five',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 6,
    'question': 'Always consult other _______ when making up your notes',
    'answer': 'Books',
    'options': 'Lecturers|Books|Students|Notes',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 7,
    'question':
        '_______ is the modification or amplification of notes taken during lectures',
    'answer': 'Note making',
    'options': 'Note books|Note making|Note taking|Long memory',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 8,
    'question':
        '________ is a technique of outlining in note taking and note making',
    'answer': 'Sentence outline',
    'options': 'Text book format|Pattern|Sentence outline|Course outline',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 9,
    'question': 'Division of an outline can be done by the use of _________',
    'answer': 'Numbers',
    'options': 'Note books|Text books|Lecture notes|Numbers',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 10,
    'question':
        'Flexibility in reading can be achieved through the following reading strategies',
    'answer': 'Skimming and scanning',
    'options':
        'Listening and speaking|Reading and writing|Skimming and scanning|None',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 11,
    'question': 'We skim because we want to make utmost use of our _________',
    'answer': 'Notes',
    'options': 'Text books|Note books|Lecture notes|Notes',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 12,
    'question': '_______ is also known as preview reading',
    'answer': 'Pre-reading',
    'options': 'Pre-reading|Over-view|Review|Skim reading',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 13,
    'question': 'Which is not required in speed reading',
    'answer': 'Active reading',
    'options':
        'Context clues|Proper eye movement|Active reading|Knowledge of one’s speed',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 14,
    'question': 'Which is of great relevance in summarizing a text',
    'answer': 'Topic sentence',
    'options':
        'Connotative sentences|Semantic fields|Meaningful clusters of words|Topic sentence',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 15,
    'question': 'Inferential comprehension requires',
    'answer': 'Making personal corrections',
    'options':
        'Making personal corrections|Collocation|Sub-vocalization|Evaluation information',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 16,
    'question': 'Which is a context clue?',
    'answer': 'Definitional sentence',
    'options':
        'Inferences|Chronological order|Writer’s purpose|Definitional sentence',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 17,
    'question': 'Connectives and determiners enable us to',
    'answer': 'Identify the functions of details',
    'options':
        'Identify background knowledge|Identify the functions of details|Determines the writer’s purpose|None of the above',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 18,
    'question': "Which can shape a writer’s arguments",
    'answer': 'All of the above',
    'options':
        'Educational background|Experiences|Environment|All of the above',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 19,
    'question': 'A major comprehension skill is',
    'answer': 'Deductive comprehension',
    'options':
        'Armchair travelling|Strategic comprehension|Deductive comprehension|Flexibility',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 20,
    'question': 'A good paragraph must contain the following in which order',
    'answer': 'Purpose, Unity, coherence, completeness and order',
    'options':
        'Purpose, Unity, coherence, completeness and order|Coherence, completeness, unity, purpose and order|Order, unity, purpose, coherence and completeness|Topic sentence, connectives, beginning, middle and ending',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 21,
    'question': 'Lots of people have problems writing conclusions because',
    'answer': 'They forget that the conclusion is the conclusion',
    'options':
        'They do not know what to say|They do not know how much to say|They forget that the conclusion is the conclusion|They sum up all the steps of the argument they have',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 22,
    'question': 'There are three stages in paragraph development',
    'answer': 'Pre-writing, writing and post-writing',
    'options':
        'The beginning, the middle and the conclusion|Pre-writing, writing and post-writing|Parallelism, antecedent and recapitulation|What, how and why',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 23,
    'question': 'There are three basic types of paragraph',
    'answer': 'Introductory, transitory and the concluding paragraph',
    'options':
        'The narrative, descriptive and argumentative paragraph|ntroductory, transitory and the concluding paragraph|The expository, persuasive and structural paragraph|The response, research and assessment paragraph',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 24,
    'question': 'A fast and effective reader makes',
    'answer': 'Very few eye movement',
    'options':
        'Very few eye movement|Rapid eye movement|No eye movement|Persistent eye movemen',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 25,
    'question': 'A fast and effective reader makes',
    'answer': 'Study pace reading',
    'options': 'Rapid reading|Study pace reading|Retrogression|Peripheral',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 26,
    'question': '________ is not a figure of speech',
    'answer': 'Ellipsis',
    'options': 'Apostrophe|Ellipsis|Irony|Bathos',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 27,
    'question': '________ uses a part of something to represent the whole',
    'answer': 'Synecdoche',
    'options': 'Methonymy|Euphemism|Synecdoche|Oxymoron',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 28,
    'question': 'The opposite of bathos is ________',
    'answer': 'Climax',
    'options': 'Litotes|Climax|Dathos|Oxymoron',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 29,
    'question':
        'We are unaware of the devices of the enemy” is an example of _______',
    'answer': 'Litotes',
    'options': 'Climax|Litotes|Euphemism|Unlitotes',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 30,
    'question': '“The pen is mightier than the sword” This statement is',
    'answer': 'Paradoxical',
    'options': 'Paradoxical|Ironical|Sarcastic|Metonymical',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 31,
    'question': '“He is an eloquent dumb man” us an example of ________',
    'answer': 'Allusion',
    'options': 'Allusion|Pun|Euphemism|Oxymoron',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 32,
    'question':
        '“To Nigeria will I steal and there I’ll steal” is an example of',
    'answer': 'Pun',
    'options': 'Allusion|Pun|Euphemism|Oxymoron',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 33,
    'question':
        'Based on their mode of operation in the process of communication, figures of speech are classified into _______ basic types',
    'answer': 'Two',
    'options': 'Three|Four|Two|Twelve',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 34,
    'question':
        'Figures of speech can _______ the reader for better understanding',
    'answer': 'Persuade',
    'options': 'Persuade|Factorize|Delude|None of the above',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 35,
    'question': '_________ is regarded as the basic unit of language',
    'answer': 'The word',
    'options': 'The alphabet|The sentence|The phrase|The word',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 36,
    'question':
        '_______ is a board concept which refer to words and their various connections and collocations',
    'answer': 'Lexis',
    'options': 'Vocabulary|Dictionary|Encyclopedia|Lexis',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 37,
    'question':
        'Words that have the same spelling, same pronunciation but different meaning are called',
    'answer': 'Homonyms',
    'options': 'Homophones|Homographs|Homonyms|Homomorphs',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 38,
    'question': 'The process of word formation that is most productive is',
    'answer': 'Derivative',
    'options': 'Compounding|Conversion|Derivative|Clipping',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 39,
    'question': 'The plural form of “Corrigendum” is',
    'answer': 'Corrigenda',
    'options': 'Corrigandums|Corrigenda|Corrgendae|Corrigendi',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 40,
    'question': 'One of these is not an irregular noun',
    'answer': 'Girl',
    'options': 'Sheep|Syllable|Girl|Stadium',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 41,
    'question': 'All of these are examples of neuter nouns except one',
    'answer': 'Hippopotamus',
    'options': 'Phenomenon|Hippopotamus|Criterion|Stadium',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 42,
    'question':
        'The plural formation that requires the addition of "e" as in formulae is called',
    'answer': 'Complex',
    'options': 'Feminine|Neuter|Masculine|Complex',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 43,
    'question':
        'A process of word formation by combining parts of two or more already existing words in the same language is referred to as',
    'answer': 'Blending',
    'options': 'Clipping|Back of formation|Coinage|Blending',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 44,
    'question': '"He is a goat" is an example of ________ meaning',
    'answer': 'Connotative',
    'options': 'Connotative|Denotative|Contextual|Reflexive',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 45,
    'question': 'A _______ is a group of words without a finite verb',
    'answer': 'Phrase',
    'options': 'Sentence|Clause|Phrase|Paragraph',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 46,
    'question': 'All these are structural types of phrases except one',
    'answer': 'Adverbial phrase',
    'options':
        'Adverbial phrase|Gerundial phrase|Participial phrase|Infinitival phrase',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 47,
    'question': '________ is not the part of the sentence that is modified',
    'answer': 'Absolute phrase',
    'options':
        'Adverbial phrase|Absolute phrase|Participial phrase|Infinitival phrase',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 48,
    'question': 'All but one belongs to the open word class in English',
    'answer': 'And',
    'options': 'Eat|Man|And|Fine',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 49,
    'question': 'Please ______ on this point',
    'answer': 'Expatiate',
    'options': 'Expantiate|Expertiate|Expatiate|Expartiate',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 50,
    'question': 'The party has only just ________',
    'answer': 'None',
    'options': 'Began|Being began|Commence|None',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 51,
    'question': 'This is just the tip of the _________',
    'answer': 'None',
    'options': 'Ice|Ice breaker|Ice bag|None',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 52,
    'question': 'The player was _______ side',
    'answer': 'Off',
    'options': 'Up|Of|Off|On the',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 53,
    'question': 'We are going on a three _________ holiday',
    'answer': 'week',
    'options': "weeks|Weeks|week|Weeks",
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 54,
    'question': 'There is ______ poverty in Nigeria',
    'answer': 'Abject',
    'options': 'Abject|Object|Ground|Grounded',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 55,
    'question': 'Adjourn collocates _________',
    'answer': 'Matter',
    'options': 'Cult|Matter|Quarrel|Magistrate',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 56,
    'question': 'To persevere means to __________',
    'answer': 'None',
    'options': 'Preserve|Moan|Cajole|None',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 57,
    'question': 'The past tense of burst is _________',
    'answer': 'None',
    'options': 'Bursts|None|Bursted|Busted',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 58,
    'question': 'You are nothing but a _______ weather friend',
    'answer': 'None',
    'options': 'Fear|Fare|Sphere|None',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 59,
    'question': 'The building was _______ to borrow from the bank',
    'answer': 'Razed',
    'options': 'Raze|Razed|Erase|Erased',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 60,
    'question': 'We needed a ________ to borrow from the bank',
    'answer': 'Collateral',
    'options': 'Surety|Guarantee|Collateral|Mortgage',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 61,
    'question': 'I know the _______ of the word',
    'answer': 'Pronunciation',
    'options': 'Pronounciation|Pronunciation|Pronunsation|Pronountiation',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 62,
    'question': 'The police action was very swift and _________',
    'answer': 'Decisive',
    'options': 'Determined|Positive|Possible|Decisive',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 63,
    'question':
        'The president with his wife and five body guards ________ attending a meeting in Paris',
    'answer': 'Is',
    'options': 'Are|Is|Were|Will',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 64,
    'question': 'The houses with their garden _______ sold',
    'answer': 'Were',
    'options': 'Was|Were|Is being|Was being',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 65,
    'question': 'The ________ hut is the one I built',
    'answer': 'Little white mud',
    'options': 'Little white mud|White little mud|White mud little|None',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 66,
    'question': 'The room is out of ________',
    'answer': 'None',
    'options': 'Bonds|Bond|Bound|None',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 67,
    'question': 'Tom used to be the best behaved student, _______',
    'answer': "Wasn’t he",
    'options': "Wasn’t he|Aren’t him?|Weren’t he?|Weren’t him?",
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 68,
    'question':
        'Each morning and evening ______ another problem for the commuter',
    'answer': 'Presents',
    'options': 'Presented|Present|Presents|Presenting',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 69,
    'question':
        'If you go travelling without permission, you may ______ your job',
    'answer': 'None',
    'options': 'Loose|Loss|Be losing|None',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 70,
    'question': '“l cant bear to see the child suffer” is ________ phrase',
    'answer': 'Infinitive',
    'options': 'Gerundic|Infinitive|Participial|None',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 71,
    'question': '“Being humble is his greatest desire” is ________ phrase',
    'answer': 'Gerund',
    'options': 'Gerund|Infinitive|Participial|Absolute',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 72,
    'question':
        'Waiting for the bride’s arrival, the bride’s-groom prayed silently is ________ phrase',
    'answer': 'Participial',
    'options': 'Gerund|Infinitive|Participial|Absolute',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 73,
    'question':
        'The most handsome boy has won the pageant is a ________ phrase',
    'answer': 'Noun phrase',
    'options':
        'Adverbial phrase|Prepositional phrase|Adjectival phrase|Noun phrase',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 74,
    'question':
        'The man "who showed me the way" is a kind is a ________ clause',
    'answer': 'Adjectival clause',
    'options': 'Adverbial clause|Adjectival clause|Noun clause|None',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
];

/* Enterprenurship */
final List<Map<String, dynamic>> ges300 = [
  {
    'id': 0,
    'question': 'Niche central entrepreneurs are ___________________',
    'options':
        'Small segment of customers|Group of customers|All of the above|Large segment of the customers|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Small segment of customers',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 1,
    'question': 'The lowering of costs through production of larger quantities',
    'options':
        'Outsourcing|Niche marketing|Economy of scale|Al of the above|Return on quantity',
    'answer': 'Economy of scale',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 2,
    'question':
        'Business practice focusing on small groups of people is called_________________',
    'options': 'Small business|Niche marketing|Diversity|Innovation|None',
    'answer': 'Niche marketing',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 3,
    'question':
        'Incremental improvement of a product is synonymous to _________________',
    'options':
        'Total quality management|Return on quality|Economy of scale|All of the above|None',
    'answer': 'Return on quality',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 4,
    'question':
        'The reason for business failure is most commonly ________________________',
    'options': 'External|Inexperience|Internal|Governmental|None',
    'answer': 'Internal',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 5,
    'question':
        'The entrepreneurship process begins with ________________________',
    'options':
        'Feasibility study|Survey|Innovative idea|Triggering event|All of the above',
    'answer': 'Innovative idea',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 6,
    'question':
        'As an entrepreneur, with which of the following do you tend to ‘fall in love’ too quickly?',
    'options':
        'New manufacturing ideas|New product ideas|New financial plans|New employees|Al of the above',
    'answer': 'New product ideas',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 7,
    'question': 'Prerequisites of becoming a successful entrepreneur include',
    'options':
        'Passion|Determination|Deep knowledge|All of the above|None of the above',
    'answer': 'All of the above',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 8,
    'question':
        'Entrepreneur’s goals state where he/she wants to be, rather than how to get there. This is why goals are written in terms of ________________________',
    'options': 'A time frame|Outcome|Challenge|Personnel|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Outcome',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 9,
    'question':
        'The reason that an entrepreneur’s business exists and the thing that the business does better than everyone else is',
    'options':
        'Opportunity|Competitive advantage|Control system|Competitive analysis|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Competitive advantage',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 10,
    'question': 'Individual ethics in the workplace are affected by',
    'options':
        'Past experiences|Ethical principles|Organisational culture|All of the above|None of the above',
    'answer': 'All of the above',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 11,
    'question':
        'The primary reason for writing business plans is ____________________',
    'options':
        'To attract capital for a start up|To make profit|To avoid risk|To make market survey|None of the above',
    'answer': 'To attract capital for a start up',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 12,
    'question':
        'A one-time payment made to become a franchise is ______________________',
    'options':
        'Disclosure fee|Franchisor fee|Franchise fee|Franchisee fee|Royalty fee',
    'answer': 'Franchise fee',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 13,
    'question': 'The on-going payments that franchisees pay to franchisors is',
    'options':
        'Franchisee fee|Royalty fee|Franchise agreement fee|All of the above|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Royalty fee',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 14,
    'question':
        'A type of franchise that represents a turnkey approach is called',
    'options':
        'Business format franchise|Due diligence franchise|Product franchise|Royalty franchise|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Business format franchise',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 15,
    'question':
        'Business valuation method based on worth of its assets is called',
    'options':
        'Income statement|Business broker|Balance sheet|Business audit|None of the above',
    'answer': 'None of the above',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 16,
    'question':
        'Entrepreneur’s cash flow equals ______________________________',
    'options':
        'Liabilities plus owner’s equity|Liability minus expenses|Receipts plus owner’s equity|Receipts minus disbursements|All of the above',
    'answer': 'Receipts minus disbursements',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 17,
    'question':
        'The reason that an entrepreneur’s business exists and the thing that the\nbusiness does\nbetter than everyone else is____________________________________',
    'options':
        'Opportunity|Competitive advantage|Control system|Competitive analysis|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Competitive advantage',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 18,
    'question':
        'A wealthy, experienced individual entrepreneur who loans money to other business owner________',
    'options':
        'Equity financier|Debt financier|Angels|Trade credit|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Angels',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 19,
    'question':
        'Psychological pricing strategy used with goods whose quality is difficult to determine by inspection is called __________________________________',
    'options':
        'Prestige pricing|Reference pricing|Price lining|Odd pricing|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Prestige pricing',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question":
        "Psychological pricing strategy used with goods whose quality is difficult to determine by inspection is called",
    "options":
        "Prestige pricing|Reference pricing|Price lining|Odd pricing|None of the above",
    "answer": "Prestige pricing",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question":
        "Setting the price of a product in a way that will alter its perception by customers is",
    "options":
        "Prestige pricing|Reference pricing|Psychological pricing|Price lining|Odd pricing",
    "answer": "Psychological pricing",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question":
        "The process of gathering all information about a particular job is called",
    "options":
        "Job description|Job analysis|Job specification|Job orientation|None of the above",
    "answer": "Job analysis",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question":
        "Direct sales promotion methods in Entrepreneurship include the following except ___",
    "options":
        "Public relations|Publicity|Special event sales|Manufacturer’s acts|None of the above",
    "answer": "Manufacturer’s acts",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "Which of the following is not a component of marketing mix",
    "options": "Place|Physical existence|People|Price|None of the above",
    "answer": "Physical existence",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question":
        "The strongest needs of an entrepreneur is called _______________",
    "options":
        "Having well established enterprise|Making good profits|Need for independence|Need for achievement|None of the above",
    "answer": "Need for independence",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "In identifying opportunities, most entrepreneurs use",
    "options":
        "Complaints from friends|Informal mechanisms|Choice comments from associates|Formal mechanisms|All of the above",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "answerIndex": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question":
        "Which of the following options is/are most appropriate for successful intrapreneurship?",
    "options":
        "Appropriate leadership characteristic|Flexibility|Visionary|Working with corporate culture|All of the above",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "answerIndex": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question":
        "Entrepreneurial endeavours consist of the following elements except",
    "options":
        "Proactiveness|Self-renewal|New business venturing|Reactiveness|Innovativeness",
    "answer": "Self-renewal",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question":
        "The time period available for the entrepreneur to create new venture is",
    "options":
        "Lead time|Business safety time|Window of opportunity|Investment time|None of the above",
    "answer": "Lead time",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question":
        "Personal entrepreneurial skills components include the following, except",
    "options":
        "Negotiation ability|Persistence ability|Change Orientation ability|Implicit discipline ability|Risk taking ability",
    "answer": "Change Orientation ability",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question":
        "Money raised by venture capitalists entrepreneurs include the following, except __________________",
    "options":
        "Equity pool|Pension funds|Foreign investors|Endowment funds|None of the above",
    "answer": "Pension funds",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question":
        "An informal investor market that can finance an entrepreneur is called",
    "options":
        "Venture capitalist|A broker|Angels|Debt factorization market|None of the above",
    "answer": "Angels",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question":
        "The form of financial transaction market when money is formally obtained by a company is called _________________________",
    "options":
        "Angels|Deal structure|Leverage market|Liquidity market|None of the above",
    "answer": "Liquidity market",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question":
        "A middle ground between starting a business and buying a going concern is to ______",
    "options":
        "Involve friends in decisions|Invest and run a franchise|Involve an intraprenuer|Involve an entrepreneur|None of the above",
    "answer": "Involve an intraprenuer",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "Emotions can help an intrapreneur to ______________",
    "options":
        "Succeed in achieving an integration of different aspects of his or her personality|Achieve group goal|Help entrepreneur in his business|Become an entrapreneur|None of the above",
    "answer": "None of the above",
    "answerIndex": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question":
        "Return on quality (ROQ) is not synonymous to the act of concentrating attention to produce quality in areas most important to customers.",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question":
        "The harvest stage of a business means when the entrepreneur removes him/herself from the business",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question":
        "An entrepreneurship locus of control does not mean his/her view and ability to determine own fate",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "Entrepreneurs are born not made",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question":
        "The bargaining power of a buyer does not affect how much attitude you have in changing your prices",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question":
        "A franchise is a small business that pays fees and royalties for exclusive rights to local distribution of the product or service.",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "Royalties are paid as a percentage of franchisee profits.",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question":
        "Serendipity means finding business opportunities the entrepreneur runs not looking for.",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question":
        "Locus of control is an entrepreneur’s attitude indicating the sense of direction",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "Intrapreneurship is not synonymous to corporate venturing",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question":
        "Amicable intrapreneurial climate is a prerequisite to successful innovation",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question":
        "The potential entrepreneur desired company opportunity identification must precede the general idea",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "A good intrapreneur makes everyone a hero",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "Handling cash flow can be crucial to entrepreneurial success",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question":
        "In forming a new venture, recruiting those in the firm usually requires established departmental structure and reporting systems.",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "question":
        "Opportunity parameters cannot be implied as barriers to entrepreneurs' new product creation and development",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "question":
        "For sustainable economic development, the spirit of intrapreneurship must not be on a volunteer basis.",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "question":
        "Entrepreneurs' time orientation does not emphasize on the long run, rather short run as applicable to managers.",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "question":
        "Entrepreneurs have been found to be more educated than the general population.",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "question": "New business venturing can simulate corporate venturing",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "question":
        "Due diligence is the process of deal evaluation in entrepreneurship",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "question": "Small business owners are entrepreneurs",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "question":
        "A business incubator is an organization designed to accelerate the growth and success of entrepreneurial companies",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "question": "Entrepreneurial personalities seem to be easily bored",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "question":
        "Stubbornness as a child cannot translate to determinations of being an entrepreneur",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "question": "Handling cash flow can be crucial to entrepreneurial success",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "question":
        "The principle of affordable loss cannot deliver the entrepreneur from the conscious determination of amount of resources committed.",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "question":
        "A bias toward quick entrepreneurial action increases the probability of creating a business but decreases the probability of success",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "question":
        "The dilemma facing political entrepreneurs can be summed up by this saying 'paralysed by analysis and extinction by instinct.'",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "question":
        "Entrepreneurs are not likely to overestimate their income and under-estimate their costs",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "question":
        "Entrepreneurs which produce only one product at a time has the advantage of being able to use a continuous-production layout.",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "question":
        "A perfectly moral entrepreneur would never allow the pull of emotion to cause him or her to act in less than entirely unreasonable manner",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "question":
        "Disciplining and controlling entrepreneurial motion is often hard work",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "question":
        "In choosing an entrepreneurial projects, emotions play more important role than intelligence",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "question":
        "Provision of different economic satisfaction is not innovation",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "question":
        "In entrepreneurship, opportunity assessment plan is not a business plan",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "question":
        "Assessment of the opportunity is not the most critical aspect of opportunity analysis",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "question": "The final business dimension is the management structure",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "question":
        "The differences in the entrepreneurial and managerial domains have increased interest in Intrapreneurship",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "question":
        "Intrapreneurship is most strongly reflected in entrepreneurial activities",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "question": "An intrapreneur must build a coalition of supporters",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "question": "Corporate venturing is not synonymous with intrapreneurship",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "question": "Organisational climate plays a vital role in innovation",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "question":
        "There is really no such thing as a ‘true entrepreneurial profile’",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "question":
        "Appropriate leadership characteristic is needed in intrapreneurship as similarly in entrepreneurship",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "question": "Entrepreneurs are not necessarily equated to inventors",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "question": "Income statement is not a snap-shot of the firm’s picture",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "question":
        "Liquidity ratios demonstrate the ability of a firm to meet up its short-term obligations",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "question": "The marketing concept places much emphasis on the customer",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "question":
        "A business solely exists to enable consumers to satisfy their needs and wants",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "question":
        "Predatory pricing is not an ethical behavior business should engage in",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "question":
        "Balance sheet gives the picture of business financial position at a particular point in time",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "question": "Liability is one of the reasons for corporation establishment",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 89,
    "question": "Entrepreneurial Corporation can be created by a statute",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "question":
        "Equity financing for entrepreneurial development can be obtained through exchange of ownership",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 91,
    "question": "Accounts receivable can provide a basis for a loan",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 92,
    "question":
        "Cash flow financing can be used by entrepreneurs as an alternative to debt financing",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "question":
        "Debt to equity ratio assesses the capital structure of entrepreneur’s firm",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "question": "Entrepreneurial business laws can be forward-looking",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "question":
        "A legal compliance business route is not necessarily against the philosophy of empowerment",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 96,
    "question": "Truth is always a wise policy in business",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 97,
    "question": "Small business owners can also be considered intrapreneurs",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "False",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 98,
    "question":
        "One of the strongest sources of entrepreneurial position power is reward power",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 99,
    "question":
        "In terms of productive roles, entrepreneurs are called creators",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 100,
    "question":
        "Financing by acquisition of plant and equipment is not called leasing",
    "options": "True|False",
    "answer": "True",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 101,
    "question":
        "Any patents, trademarks , copyright or trade secrets held by the entrepreneur is known as",
    "options":
        "Disclosure document|Patent|Intellectual property|None of the mentioned",
    "answer": "Intellectual property",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 102,
    "question":
        "The organization will never be able to make the necessary changes without_________",
    "options":
        "Top management commitment|Employees|Workers|None of the mentioned",
    "answer": "Top management commitment",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 103,
    "question": "The ways entrepreneurs make decisions.",
    "options":
        "Entrepreneurial domain|Reverse brain storming|Heuristics|Reverse brain storming",
    "answer": "Entrepreneurial domain",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 104,
    "question":
        "A trademark is a word, symbol, name or device that a business uses to identify its goods.",
    "options":
        "A legal protection for information on foreign products.|Legal protection for intellectual works.|Legal protection for a U.S. product exported to another country.",
    "answer": "Legal protection for intellectual works.",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 105,
    "question": "locus of control is",
    "options": "A feeling|Attitude|Attribute|None of the above",
    "answer": "Attribute",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 106,
    "question": "Licensing arrangements have",
    "options":
        "Low risk process involved|Easy way to generate incremental income|Several pitfalls|All of the above",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 107,
    "question":
        "Personal characteristics to be a successful entrepreneur includes",
    "options":
        "Understanding environment|Creating management options|Encourage open discussion|All of the above",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 108,
    "question": "International entrepreneurship is",
    "options":
        "Licensing|Exporting|Both of the mentioned options|None of the two mentioned",
    "answer": "Both of the mentioned options",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 109,
    "question":
        "Which of the following is not a characteristic that is helpful for an entrepreneur to have?",
    "options": "Self-esteem|Caution|Drive|Optimism",
    "answer": "Caution",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 110,
    "question": "Hindrance for going in the international business is known as",
    "options": "Synergy|Turn key point|Trade barrier|Minority interest",
    "answer": "Trade barrier",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 111,
    "question":
        "A set of reasons for engaging in a particular behavior, especially human behavior is known as _____________.",
    "options": "Values|Vision|Entrepreneurship|Motivation",
    "answer": "Motivation",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 112,
    "question":
        "Which of the following techniques is an excellent method for initially screening ideas and concepts in addition to generating new ideas?",
    "options":
        "Focus group|Brain storming|Problem inventory analysis|Reverse brainstorming",
    "answer": "Focus group",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 113,
    "question":
        "The creative process for problem solving that involves making the strange familiar in first step and then making the familiar strange through personal, direct or symbolic analogy is called _________.",
    "options": "Synectics|Gordon method|Checklist method|Scientific method",
    "answer": "Synectics",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 114,
    "question":
        "When the multiplicity of environments become too complex to handle, the international entrepreneurs often __________.",
    "options":
        "Go for mergers|Diversify|Decentralize operations|Sale out the foreign business",
    "answer": "Decentralize operations",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 115,
    "question":
        "An entrepreneur into the hosiery business found out the reason his hosiery was not selling was due to its color. What could be the best source of this information?",
    "options": "Supplier|Retailer|Competition|Government bureau",
    "answer": "Retailer",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 116,
    "question":
        "In some countries, point of purchase displays are not allowed in retail stores. Such differences are studied by international entrepreneurs under __________ environment.",
    "options": "Economic|Political|Cultural|Technological",
    "answer": "Cultural",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 117,
    "question":
        "Entrepreneurial success has been significant because of the culture and the political and economic systems in _________.",
    "options":
        "European countries|Asian countries|Transition economies|Middle east",
    "answer": "Asian countries",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 118,
    "question":
        "Having more than 50% ownership position that provides the entrepreneur with managerial control is called ___________.",
    "options":
        "Joint venture|Majority interest|Horizontal merger|Diversified activity merger",
    "answer": "Majority interest",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 119,
    "question":
        "The under-developed or lesser developed countries need manufacturing technology and infrastructure and yet do not want to turn over substantial portion of their economy to foreign ownership. Which of the following is a solution to this dilemma?",
    "options":
        "Management contract|Indirect exporting|Licensing|Turn-key project",
    "answer": "Turn-key project",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 120,
    "question":
        "The development of a new venture based on an inventor's work often requires _________.",
    "options":
        "Expertise of an entrepreneur|Heavy investment from financers|Skilled human resources|Highly educated staff",
    "answer": "Expertise of an entrepreneur",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 121,
    "question":
        "__________ is the process in marketing of dividing a market into distinct subsets (segments) that behave in the same way or have similar needs.",
    "options":
        "Target Market|Market Analysis|Market Segmentation|All of the Above",
    "answer": "Market Segmentation",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 122,
    "question":
        "A business where an individual is both the owner and conductor of the business affairs is called __________.",
    "options": "Sole Proprietorship|Partnership|Corporation|None of the above",
    "answer": "Sole Proprietorship",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 123,
    "question":
        "In _________________, the entrepreneur has the right to sell any assets.",
    "options":
        "Proprietorship|Partnership|Limited Liability Company|None of the given options",
    "answer": "Proprietorship",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 124,
    "question":
        "_________________ are lists of the general tasks, or functions, and responsibilities of a position.",
    "options": "Job Specifications|Job descriptions|Job Requirements|Jobholder",
    "answer": "Job descriptions",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 125,
    "question":
        "A ________________ can be a budget, a plan for spending and saving future income.",
    "options":
        "Marketing Plan|Financial Plan|Production Plan|Organizational Plan",
    "answer": "Financial Plan",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 126,
    "question":
        "________________ involves an interest-bearing instrument, usually a loan, the payment of which is only indirectly related to sales and profits.",
    "options":
        "Equity Financing|Internal or External Funds|Banking Funds|Debt Financing",
    "answer": "Debt Financing",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 127,
    "question":
        "The idea and actions that explain how a firm will make its profits refers to",
    "options": "Mission|Goal|Strategy|Objective",
    "answer": "Strategy",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 128,
    "question": "SBIR stands for:",
    "options":
        "Small Business Information Research|Small Business Innovation Research|Small Business Intelligent Research|Small Business Inventory Research",
    "answer": "Small Business Innovation Research",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 129,
    "question":
        "_______________ is what the 'W' in the SWOT analysis stands for.",
    "options": "Wedge|Work/life|Worth of Business|Weakness",
    "answer": "Weakness",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 130,
    "question": "Benefits can focus on which of these?",
    "options":
        "Value and Cost|Imitation and Innovation|Internal and External aspects|None of the given options",
    "answer": "Value and Cost",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 131,
    "question":
        "An entrepreneur's primary motivation for starting a business is",
    "options": "To make money.|To be independent|To be famous|To be powerful",
    "answer": "To be independent",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 132,
    "question": "To be successful in an entrepreneurial venture, you need",
    "options": "Money|Luck|Hard work|A good idea",
    "answer": "Luck",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 133,
    "question": "Entrepreneurs are best as",
    "options": "Managers|Venture capitalists|Planners|Doers",
    "answer": "Doers",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 134,
    "question":
        "A successful entrepreneur relies on which of the following for critical management advice",
    "options":
        "Internal management team|External management professionals|Financial sources|No one",
    "answer": "External management professionals",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 135,
    "question": "Entrepreneurs are:",
    "options":
        "High risk takers|Moderate risk takers|Small risk takers|Doesn't matter",
    "answer": "Moderate risk takers",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 136,
    "question": "Entrepreneurs typically form",
    "options":
        "Service businesses|Manufacturing companies|Constructive companies|A variety of ventures",
    "answer": "A variety of ventures",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 137,
    "question": "Entrepreneurs:",
    "options":
        "Are the life of the party|Are bores at a cocktail party|Will never go to parties|Just fit into the crowd at a party",
    "answer": "Just fit into the crowd at a party",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 138,
    "question": "Entrepreneurs and venture capitalists:",
    "options":
        "Get along well|Are the best friends|Are cordial friends|Are in conflict",
    "answer": "Are in conflict",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 139,
    "question":
        "An entrepreneur's primary motivation for high ego and need for achievement is based upon a relationship with:",
    "options": "Spouse|Mother|Father|Children",
    "answer": "Father",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 140,
    "question":
        "An individual usually begins his or her first significant entrepreneurial business enterprise at what age",
    "options": "Teens|Twenties|Forties|Fifties",
    "answer": "Forties",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 141,
    "question": "NAFTA stands for:",
    "options":
        "North American Free Trade Agreements|North Asian Free Trade Agreements|National Asian Free Trade Agreements|National American Free Trade Agreements",
    "answer": "North American Free Trade Agreements",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 142,
    "question":
        "The factor______________ is probably the most prevalent reason for mergers.",
    "options": "Taxation|Economies of scale|Inflation|Mergers",
    "answer": "Economies of scale",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 143,
    "question":
        "A _____________ merger is a combination of two firms producing the same products but selling them in different geographic markets.",
    "options":
        "Diversified Activity Merger|Product Extension Merger|Vertical Merger|Market Extension Merger",
    "answer": "Market Extension Merger",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 144,
    "question":
        "One of the most frequent reasons an entrepreneur forms a joint venture is to share the .",
    "options": "Resources|Cost|Cost and risk of a project|Profit",
    "answer": "Cost and risk of a project",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 145,
    "question":
        " involves having a foreign purchaser in the local market or using an export management firm.",
    "options":
        "Direct Exporting|Indirect Exporting|Management Contracts|Turn-Key Projects",
    "answer": "Indirect Exporting",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 146,
    "question":
        "The measures the payments that flow between any individual country and all other countries.",
    "options":
        "International Business|Economies of Scales|Balance of Payment|None of the given options",
    "answer": "Balance of Payment",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 147,
    "question":
        "__________ is an entrepreneurial type who quickly identifies new promising business opportunities but rarely, if ever, follows through on the opportunity to create a successful new venture.",
    "options": "Simplicity Sue|Shotgun Sam|Hidden Agenda Harry|Inventor Irving",
    "answer": "Shotgun Sam",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 148,
    "question":
        "One study found that the typical minority business owner was the",
    "options":
        "Oldest child in a blue-collar family and married.|Oldest child in a white-collar family and married.|Youngest child in a blue-collar family and married.|Youngest child in a white-collar family and married.",
    "answer": "Oldest child in a blue-collar family and married.",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 149,
    "question": "Traditional managers are:",
    "options":
        "Deals with mistakes and failures|Tries to avoid mistakes and surprises|Attempts to hide risky projects from view until ready|None of the given Options",
    "answer": "Tries to avoid mistakes and surprises",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 150,
    "question": "Enterperneurs are:",
    "options": "Moderate risk taker|High risk taker|Avoidance|Both b and c",
    "answer": "Moderate risk taker",
    "answerIndex": 0,
  },
  {
    "id": 151,
    "question": "Risk decisions are often postponed until",
    "options":
        "Hard facts can be gathered or a consultant hired to illuminate the unknown.|Hard facts can be gathered or an auditor hired to illuminate the unknown.|There is no need to gather facts and hired a consultant/auditor|None of the given options",
    "answer":
        "Hard facts can be gathered or a consultant hired to illuminate the unknown.",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 152,
    "question":
        "_________________ is one method of stimulating, and then capitalizing on, individuals in an organization who think that something can be done differently and better.",
    "options":
        "Strategic Orientation|Capitalization|Intrapreneurship|Management",
    "answer": "Intrapreneurship",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 153,
    "question":
        "The typical _________________ has a climate and reward system that favor conservative decision making.",
    "options":
        "Entrepreneurship culture|Corporate culture|Intrapreneurial culture|None of the given options",
    "answer": "Corporate culture",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 154,
    "question":
        "Female entrepreneurs normally start their venture at the age of _____________ years.",
    "options": "35-45|25-30|20-25|40-45",
    "answer": "35-45",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 155,
    "question":
        "Male entrepreneurs normally start their venture at the age of____________ years.",
    "options": "20-25|25-35|40-50|After the age of retirement.",
    "answer": "25-35",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 156,
    "question":
        "The ________________ is the process through which innovation develops and commercializes through entrepreneurial activity, which in turn stimulates economic growth.",
    "options":
        "Product-evolution process|Technological innovations|Breakthrough innovations|None of the given options",
    "answer": "Product-evolution process",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 157,
    "question":
        "A____________________ is a type of company formed from research and development that usually does not go public.",
    "options": "Foundation|Life-Style Firm|High-Potential Venture|Both b and c",
    "answer": "Foundation",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 158,
    "question":
        "_____________ involve such things as writing, listening, oral presentations, coaching and technical know-how.",
    "options":
        "Business Management skills|Personal entrepreneurial skills|Technical skills|None of the given options",
    "answer": "Technical skills",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 159,
    "question":
        "The ___________________ means to do things in his or her own way and time.",
    "options":
        "Need per independence|Need for achievement|Personal values|Ethics",
    "answer": "Need per independence",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 160,
    "question":
        "_______________ is a reason or set of reasons for engaging in a particular behavior, especially human behavior.",
    "options": "Moral value|Act|Motivation|None of the options",
    "answer": "Motivation",
    "answerIndex": 2,
  },
  {
    "id": 161,
    "question": "The _______ plan shows whether the business is economically feasible or not.",
    "options": "Financial|Business|Economic|Marketing",
    "answer": "Business",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 162,
    "question": "In which of the following, the ownership of venture is reflected by ownership of shares of stock?",
    "options": "Partnership|Limited partnership|Corporation|Proprietorship",
    "answer": "Corporation",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 163,
    "question": "Bankers say that most businesses fail because of the _____ inability to plan properly.",
    "options": "Investor's|Marketer's|Entrepreneur's|Consultant's",
    "answer": "Entrepreneur's",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 164,
    "question": "The _________ of a venture could be that the company has experience in related business.",
    "options": "Strength|Weakness|Opportunity|Threat",
    "answer": "Strength",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 165,
    "question": "The marketing plan should focus on strategies and for the first year, goals and strategies should be projected __________.",
    "options": "Daily|Weekly|Monthly|Quarterly",
    "answer": "Monthly",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 166,
    "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of marketing plan?",
    "options": "It should provide a strategy to accomplish the company mission|It should provide for the use of existing resources|It should be simple and short|It should be rigid",
    "answer": "It should be rigid",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 167,
    "question": "Secondary data can be obtained from all of the following sources, except:",
    "options": "Internet|Magazine|Bureau of statistics|Focus group",
    "answer": "Focus group",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 168,
    "question": "Which of the following is one of the simplest form and lowest in entry costs.",
    "options": "Direct mail marketing|Online marketing|Sales promotion|Export marketing",
    "answer": "Direct mail marketing",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 169,
    "question": "In ________, the death of entrepreneur results in the termination of venture.",
    "options": "Proprietorship|Limited company|Limited partnership|Corporation",
    "answer": "Proprietorship",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 170,
    "question": "In partnership, the ability to raise capital depends on the __________ of the business.",
    "options": "Expansion|Success|Size|Nature",
    "answer": "Success",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 171,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT recognized an important component to organizational vision?",
    "options": "The vision should be built on a foundation of the organization's core values and beliefs.|The vision should elaborate a purpose for the organization.|The vision should include a brief summary of what the organization does.|The vision should specify detailed and short-term goals.",
    "answer": "The vision should specify detailed and short-term goals.",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 172,
    "question": "Which of the following components of organizational vision and mission statements tells how the organizational unit is responsive to societal, community, and environmental issues?",
    "options": "Customer|Market|Self-Concept|Concern for public image",
    "answer": "Concern for public image",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 173,
    "question": "Which of the following dimensions of organizational culture describes the degree to which employees are expected to do their jobs with precision, thorough analysis, and attention to detail?",
    "options": "Innovation and risk-taking|Team orientation|Aggressiveness|Attention to detail",
    "answer": "Attention to detail",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 174,
    "question": "Which of the following does NOT represent a method through which organizational culture is learned?",
    "options": "Stories|Conflict|Rituals|Material symbols",
    "answer": "Conflict",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 175,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT recognized as an important purpose of a business plan?",
    "options": "Development tool for organizational founders|Vision and mission clarification|Planning and evaluation guidelines|All of the selections are recognized as important purposes of a business plan.",
    "answer": "All of the selections are recognized as important purposes of a business plan.",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 176,
    "question": "All of the following are recognized as criticisms of planning EXCEPT:",
    "options": "Planning may create rigidity|Planning focuses entrepreneurs' attention on tomorrow's survival but not today's competition|Plans can't be developed for a dynamic environment|Formal planning reinforces success, which may lead to failure",
    "answer": "Planning focuses entrepreneurs' attention on tomorrow's survival but not today's competition",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 177,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT recognized as a major area that should be included in a business plan?",
    "options": "Executive summary|Corporate culture differences|Analysis of the opportunity|Analysis of the context",
    "answer": "Corporate culture differences",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 178,
    "question": "Which of the following does NOT relate to the analysis of opportunity section of a business plan?",
    "options": "Sizing up the market by describing the demographics of the target market|Analyzing current and proposed and governmental rules and regulations that might potentially have an impact on the entrepreneurial venture.|Describing and evaluating industry trends|Identifying and evaluating competitors",
    "answer": "Analyzing current and proposed and governmental rules and regulations that might potentially have an impact on the entrepreneurial venture.",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 179,
    "question": "All of the following are important elements of the financial data and projections section of a business plan EXCEPT:",
    "options": "SWOT analysis|Projected income statements|Break-even analysis|Cost controls",
    "answer": "SWOT analysis",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 180,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT an important characteristic when writing a business plan?",
    "options": "Clear, realistic financial projections|Detailed market research|Brief summary since the investor is more interested in the details in the business plan.|Proof of vision",
    "answer": "Brief summary since the investor is more interested in the details in the business plan.",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 181,
    "question": "A(n) ___________ is a form of organization in which the owner maintains complete control over the business and is personally liable for business debts.",
    "options": "Sole proprietorship|General partnership|Corporation|Limited liability company",
    "answer": "Sole proprietorship",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 182,
    "question": "A(n) _____________ is a form of business organization in which two or more business owners share the management and risk of the business",
    "options": "Limited liability company|General partnership|Corporation|Sole proprietorship",
    "answer": "General partnership",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 183,
    "question": "A(n) ____________ is a form of business organization in which there are general partners and limited liability partners.",
    "options": "Sole proprietorship|General partnership|Limited liability partnership|Corporation",
    "answer": "Limited liability partnership",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 184,
    "question": "A(n) ___________ is a legal business entity that is separate from its owners and managers.",
    "options": "Sole proprietorship|General partnership|Corporation|Limited liability company",
    "answer": "Corporation",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 185,
    "question": "A(n) ____________ is a form of legal protection for a distinctive word, name, phrase, logo, symbol, design, slogan, or any combination of these elements.",
    "options": "Trademark|Patent|Contract|Procedure",
    "answer": "Trademark",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 186,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of the three different types of patents?",
    "options": "Utility patent|Design patent|Plant patent|All of the selections if a valid type of patent.",
    "answer": "All of the selections if a valid type of patent.",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 187,
    "question": "Which of the following is recognized as the most common type of patent?",
    "options": "Utility patent|Design patent|Plant patent|Cultural patent",
    "answer": "Utility patent",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 188,
    "question": "All of the following are signals of potential decline in organizational performance EXCEPT:",
    "options": "Poor communication within the organization|Intolerance of work incompetence|Fear of conflict and taking risks|Negative cash flow",
    "answer": "Intolerance of work incompetence",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 189,
    "question": "All of the following are recognized as important people practices of successful organizations EXCEPT:",
    "options": "Employment security|Selective hiring|Increased status differences|Training",
    "answer": "Increased status differences",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 190,
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT a characteristic of an effective team?",
    "options": "External support|Clear goals|Irrelevant skills|Mutual trust",
    "answer": "Irrelevant skills",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 191,
    "question": "In brainstorming, which of the following is true?",
    "options": "No criticism is allowed|Quantity of ideas is desired|None of the mentioned options|Both of the mentioned options",
    "answer": "Both of the mentioned options",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 192,
    "question": "Which of the following is a technique that asks questions about objects or ideas in an effort to develop a new idea?",
    "options": "Heuristics|Matrix charting|Forced relationships|Attribute listing",
    "answer": "Forced relationships",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 193,
    "question": "What is the term used for the process of developing a solution?",
    "options": "Big-Dream approach|Parameter Analysis|Creative synthesis|None of the above",
    "answer": "Creative synthesis",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 194,
    "question": "Which of the following factors are involved in perceived benefits/risks?",
    "options": "Utility to customer|Consumption habits|Buying motives|All of the above",
    "answer": "All of the above",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 195,
    "question": "What is a patent?",
    "options": "A document between government and an inventor|Grants holder protection from others making, using, or selling similar idea|A public domain|None of the above",
    "answer": "Grants holder protection from others making, using, or selling similar idea",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 196,
    "question": "The term entrepreneur came from:",
    "options": "Latin|French|English (UK)|none of the given option",
    "answer": "French",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 197,
    "question": "The term entrepreneur is translated as:",
    "options": "between-giver|between-taker|receiver|giver",
    "answer": "between-taker",
    "answerIndex": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 198,
    "question": "The period in which the money person entered into a contract with the go-between to sell his goods is known as:",
    "options": "middle aes|18th century|17th century|earliest period",
    "answer": "earliest period",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 199,
    "question": "_________ viewed the entrepreneur as a risk taker who 'buy(s. at an uncertain price, therefore operating at a risk'",
    "options": "Eli Whitney|Edward hariman|Richard cantillon|Thomas Edison",
    "answer": "Richard cantillon",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 200,
    "question": "_________ is a professional money manager who makes risk investment from a pool of equity capital to obtain a high rate of return on investments",
    "options": "venture capitalist|entrepreneur|businessman|buyer",
    "answer": "venture capitalist",
    "answerIndex": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 201,
    "question": "In the ---------- century, the notion of an entrepreneur as an innovator was established.",
    "options": "17th century|late 19th century|middle of the 20th century|18th century",
    "answer": "middle of the 20th century",
    "answerIndex": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 202,
    "question": "In almost all definitions of entrepreneurship there is agreement that we are talking about a kind of behavior that includes:",
    "options": "initiative taking|the organizing and reorganizing or social/economic mechanisms to turn resources and situations to practical account.|the acceptance of risk or failure|all of the given option",
    "answer": "all of the given option",
    "answerIndex": 3
  }
];

/* Computer Appreciation */
final List<Map<String, dynamic>> ges101 = [
  {
    'id': 0,
    'question': '............. is not part of the status bar',
    'answer': 'drop cap',
    'options': 'page number|line|column|section|drop cap',
    'answerIndex': 4,
  },
  {
    'id': 1,
    'question': '………….. is not part of the status bar',
    'answer': 'page number',
    'options': 'page number|line|column|section|drop cap',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 2,
    'question': 'Convert 10610 to base 2',
    'answer': '01101010 2',
    'options': '0101011 2|110101 2|101010 2|01101010 2|01011010 2',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 3,
    'question':
        'Hierarchical model, network model and relational model are all parts of',
    'answer': 'database model',
    'options':
        'system model|network model|database model|data structure|data architecture',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 4,
    'question':
        'The Drag and Drop feature can be turn on or off in the Tools command',
    'answer': 'true',
    'options': 'false|true|not correct|not true|none of the above',
    'answerIndex': 1,
  },
  {
    'id': 5,
    'question': 'The control buttons on the title bar include all except',
    'answer': 'none of the above',
    'options': 'restore|minimise|maximise|close|none of the above',
    'answerIndex': 4,
  },
  {
    'id': 6,
    'question': '----------- provides a list of toggle options',
    'answer': 'Check boxes',
    'options': 'List boxes|Text boxes|Check boxes|Option button|Drop down list',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 7,
    'question': 'The F4 command in DOS will',
    'answer': 'delete all characters in buffer to the last command',
    'options':
        'redisplay buffer|delete all|delete all characters in buffer to the last command|redisplay all characters|Do nothing',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 8,
    'question':
        'The area that first appear on the screen after the system boots is',
    'answer': 'desktop',
    'options': 'wallpaper|screen saver|background|desktop|windows OS',
    'answerIndex': 3,
  },
  {
    'id': 9,
    'question': 'Convert 11110101 2 to base 8',
    'answer': '172 8',
    'options': '174 8|712 8|721 8|271 8|172 8',
    'answerIndex': 4,
  },
  {
    'id': 10,
    'question': 'The splitting of text to fit in a cell is called',
    'answer': 'word wrap',
    'options': 'word wrap|insertion point|text wrap|name boxing|auto fill',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 11,
    'question': 'The command VOL in command prompt is used to',
    'options':
        'increase the system volume|display a disk volume label and serial number|display the disk volume level|display all files in the volume|display nothing',
    'answer': 'display a disk volume label and serial number',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 12,
    'question': 'Which one is the odd one out?',
    'options':
        'drawing toolbar|status bar|formula bar|formatting toolbar|standard tool',
    'answer': 'standard tool',
    'answerIndex': 4,
  },
  {
    'id': 13,
    'question': 'What is an advantage of electronic data processing?',
    'answer': 'All of the above',
    'options':
        'Faster processing speed|Automatic data processing as it enters the system|Accurate data output|Timely availability of results|All of the above',
    'answerIndex': 4,
  },
  {
    'id': 14,
    'question': 'A machine language is in 0 and 1',
    'options': 'true|false|ASCII language|all of the above|none of the above',
    'answer': 'true',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 15,
    'question': 'Which is not part of a standard keyboard?',
    'options':
        'numeric keys|alphanumeric keys|text keys|function keys|none of the above',
    'answer': 'text keys',
    'answerIndex': 2,
  },
  {
    'id': 16,
    'question':
        'Deleting the original item does not automatically delete the shortcut.',
    'answer': 'True',
    'options': 'True|False|Not true|Probably|None of the above',
    'answerIndex': 0,
  },
  {
    'id': 17,
    'question':
        'The data capture technique best suitable for examinations and questionnaires is',
    'options':
        'optical character recognition|magnetic character recognition|mark sensing device|Kimball tags|magnetic tags',
    'answer': 'mark sensing device',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 18,
    'question':
        'The processing of data by consisting of a keyboard actuated by a machine operator is called',
    'options':
        'electronic data processing|manual data processing|human data processing|machine data processing|mechanical data processing',
    'answer': 'mechanical data processing',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 19,
    'question':
        'file handler, formatter, and sort/list utility are all examples of',
    'options': 'translators|applications|OS|utilities|computer tools',
    'answer': 'utilities',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 20,
    'question': 'The keyboard command to close a window is',
    'options': 'CTRL + X|CTRL + W|CTRL + Y|CTRL + SHIFT + DELETE|CTRL + END',
    'answer': 'CTRL + W',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 21,
    'question': 'The move through a cell is achieved through',
    'options':
        'use of the arrow keys|selecting with the mouse|use of the tab key|a, b and c are correct|none of the above',
    'answer': 'a, b and c are correct',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 22,
    'question': 'The formula bar in excel display',
    'options':
        'the content of an active cell|the formula in a cell|the name of the active cell|a and b is correct|a, b, c is correct',
    'answer': 'a and b is correct',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 23,
    'question': 'A temporary storage area in computer memory is called',
    'options': 'RAM|ROM|primary memory|secondary storage|buffer',
    'answer': 'buffer',
    'answerIndex': 5
  },
  {
    'id': 24,
    'question': 'To add cell A2 & A4 use ……',
    'options': '=Sum (A1:A3)|Sum (A2:A4)|=SUM(A2;A4)|=A1:A3|None of the above',
    'answer': '=SUM(A2;A4)',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 25,
    'question': 'The command dir t*.* will',
    'options':
        'display s*.* is not an internal or external command|display an error message|display all dir and files that starts with letter t|display t*.* is a file|display t*.* does not exist',
    'answer': 'display all dir and files that starts with letter t',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 26,
    'question': 'The cls command in DOS',
    'options':
        'shutdown the computer|shutdown the system|display all directory with cls name|restart the program|clear the screen',
    'answer': 'clear the screen',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 27,
    'question': 'The roller on a PS2 mouse enables the user to',
    'options':
        'scroll up and down|saves 35% of the time spent scrolling a document|zoom in and out a graphic application|a, b and c is correct|only b and c is correct',
    'answer': 'a, b and c is correct',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 28,
    'question': 'Triple click on a mouse selects',
    'options': 'a text|a line or paragraph|a word|all|a letter',
    'answer': 'a line or paragraph',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 28,
    'question': 'To expand the length of a column',
    'options':
        'move the mouse pointer to the line between the columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions|move the mouse pointer to the line between the rows, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions|move the mouse pointer away from the line between the columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions|move the mouse pointer to the line away from columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions|none of the above.',
    'answer':
        'move the mouse pointer to the line between the columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 29,
    'question': 'The command DISKCOPY A:B will',
    'options':
        'copy the content of A to B|copy the content of drive A to a specified drive|copy the content of a and await the next instruction|copy the content in all drives|just copy',
    'answer': 'copy the content of A to B',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 30,
    'question': 'Primary memory will usually contain',
    'options':
        'the program currently executed and data needed by the program|a faster access time|a smaller size|a, b, c is correct|only a and b is correct',
    'answer': '5',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 31,
    'question': 'Which of these is not a type of printer',
    'options':
        'dot matrix printer|digital printer|ink jet printer|laser printer|colour ink printer',
    'answer': 'colour ink printer',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 32,
    'question':
        'A device that checks whether a box has been ticked or selected is called',
    'options':
        'magnetic character device|mark sensing device|optical character device|credit card|Kimball tag',
    'answer': 'mark sensing device',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 33,
    'question': 'The function of the F5 key',
    'options':
        'redisplay buffer|delete all characters|stores the current line for editing|delete entire lines|edit entire line for formatting',
    'answer': 'stores the current line for editing',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 34,
    'question': 'The use of unique bar and spaces in data capture is found in',
    'options': 'MICR code|OCR code|BAR CODE|CREDIT CARD CODE|ATM CODE',
    'answer': 'BAR CODE',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 35,
    'question': 'The intersection between a column and a row is called',
    'options': 'midpoint|centre point|cell|area|excel spread sheet',
    'answer': 'cell',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 36,
    'question': 'Ctrl +shift + A will …………',
    'options':
        'continue Execution complete|slow the execution|stop execution completely|paused execution for a while|format letters as all capital',
    'answer': 'format letters as all capital',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 37,
    'question':
        'In MS word 2003 pagination and formatting can be automatically done',
    'options': 'false|not true|a and b is correct|all of the above|True',
    'answer': 'True',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 38,
    'question': 'To access the world wide web, a computer system needs to have',
    'options':
        'internet surfing ability|internet protocol name|a web browser|an isp connector|internet locator',
    'answer': 'a web browser',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 39,
    'question':
        'The bar that provides short cut for menu and frequently used command is',
    'options':
        'standard tool bar|menu bar|formatting tool bar|formula bar|status bar',
    'answer': 'standard tool bar',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 40,
    'question':
        'The bars that allows the screen to move left, right, top and bottom are',
    'options':
        'vertical and alignment bar|alignment and movement bar|movement and vertical bar|horizontal and movement bar|vertical and horizontal bar',
    'answer': 'vertical and horizontal bar',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 41,
    'question': 'The primary steps in data processing are all except',
    'options':
        'information output|information input|processing of data|data storage|all except d',
    'answer': 'data storage',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 42,
    'question':
        'Optic coaxial cable is to local area network as micro wave is to',
    'options': 'LAN|WAN|GAN|large area NETWORK|wide aperture network',
    'answer': 'large area NETWORK',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 43,
    'question': 'The use of very large-scale integrated circuits is common in',
    'options':
        'fourth generation computers|third generation computers|second generation computers|first generation computers|fifth generation',
    'answer': 'third generation computers',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 44,
    'question': 'The main purpose of storing data is for',
    'options':
        'creating a database|processing|data usage|none of the above|all of the above',
    'answer': 'processing',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 45,
    'question': 'The first page a user logged on to is called',
    'options': 'welcome page|web site|internet page|home page|web page',
    'answer': 'home page',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 46,
    'question': 'The total number of columns in Microsoft Office Excel 2003 is',
    'options': '18834|18845|168435|164853|none of the above',
    'answer': 'none of the above',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 47,
    'question': 'The work area in Microsoft word is known as',
    'options':
        'document area|work space|document space|space area|none of the above',
    'answer': 'document area',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 48,
    'question': 'The right button on the mouse is use to',
    'options':
        'execute a command|call for options|open an application|format a document|all of the above',
    'answer': 'call for options',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 49,
    'question': 'Charts are used to view data in Microsoft office excel',
    'options': 'false|true|not true|all of the above|none of the above',
    'answer': 'true',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 50,
    'question':
        'The fill handle is used to generate a formula sequence to adjacent cells',
    'options': 'true|false|all of the above|none of the above',
    'answer': 'true',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 51,
    'question':
        'The auto texting feature of Microsoft word helps in automatic insertion of images',
    'options': 'true|false|not of the above',
    'answer': 'false',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 52,
    'question': 'Procedure oriented languages is common to',
    'options':
        'high level language|low level language|foreign language|list logic processing language|all of the above',
    'answer': 'high level language',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 53,
    'question': 'Which of these is not a data element of a database',
    'options': 'field|file|records|character|directory',
    'answer': 'directory',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 54,
    'question':
        'Database architecture can be viewed in respect to organization of data',
    'options': 'not true|not entirely true|true|false|none of the above',
    'answer': 'true',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 55,
    'question': 'Commercial facilities of WAN include',
    'options': 'e-governance|view data|e-banking|e-solutions|e-travel',
    'answer': 'view data',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 56,
    'question': 'FTP is an acronym for',
    'options':
        'file translate process|file transfer process|file transfer protocol|file translate protocol|file transfer partition',
    'answer': 'file transfer protocol',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 57,
    'question': '-------- is not a file extension name',
    'options': '.cdr|.doc|.ppt|.bas|none of the above',
    'answer': 'none of the above',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 58,
    'question': 'The EXIT command in DOS command prompt will',
    'options':
        'display all dir folders|shut down the computer|quit the CMD.EXE program|all of the above|C and D are correct',
    'answer': 'quit the CMD.EXE program',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 59,
    'question':
        'The movement of the cursor to the next line as it gets to the end of the margin in the document area is called',
    'options':
        'cursor movement|word wrap|text wrap|enter new line|neither A, B, C nor D',
    'answer': 'word wrap',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 60,
    'question': 'Multiple windows that are opened are indicated on the',
    'options':
        'menu bar|standard tools bar|notification bar|task pane|task bar',
    'answer': 'task bar',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 61,
    'question': 'A file in Microsoft office excel is saved as a',
    'options':
        'spreadsheet|excel file doc.|workbook|spread sheet book|all of the above',
    'answer': 'workbook',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 62,
    'question': 'The keyboard command to find a text in a document is',
    'options': 'ctrl + A|ctrl + F|ctrl + G|ctrl + H|ctrl + V',
    'answer': 'ctrl + F',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 63,
    'question':
        'The screen of Microsoft word is made up of the following except ……………',
    'options':
        'Title bar|Menu bar|Standard toolbar|Formatting toolbar|page setup bar',
    'answer': 'page setup bar',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 64,
    'question':
        'The movement of full or part of document from one place to another leaving the original copy is called',
    'options': 'Cutting|Copying|Pasting|Editing|All of the above',
    'answer': 'Copying',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 65,
    'question': 'What is the function of the shift + F2 key?',
    'options': 'Do nothing|Copy text|Edit page|Paste all|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Edit page',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 66,
    'question':
        'The keyboard key that deletes all the characters in a buffer up to the last character is',
    'options': 'F4|F2|F6|F8|F12',
    'answer': 'F4',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 67,
    'question': 'The maximum number of sheets in a workbook is',
    'options': '256|255|265|266|258',
    'answer': '256',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 68,
    'question': 'To add cell A2 & A4 use ……',
    'options': '=Sum (A1:A3)|Sum (A2:A4)|=A1:A3|None of the above|=SUM(A2;A4)',
    'answer': 'Sum (A2:A4)',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 69,
    'question':
        'Excel is an electronic spread sheet to calculate, analyze and view data',
    'options': 'Very true|Not all through|Not absolutely true|Very wrong|False',
    'answer': 'Very true',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 70,
    'question': 'Moving between cells is achieved through',
    'options':
        'press the tab key on the keyboard|use the mouse to select the next cell|use of any of the four arrows keys|none of the above|all of the above except d',
    'answer': 'all of the above except d',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 71,
    'question': 'The Fill Handle is to',
    'options':
        'fill data into a row or column|generate the sequence data in a row or column|a and b is correct|only a is correct|only b is correct',
    'answer': 'a and b is correct',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 72,
    'question':
        'Font, font style, double strike through, emboss, subscript and all cap are all check boxes in',
    'options': 'Edit|View|File|Menu|Format',
    'answer': 'Format',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 73,
    'question':
        'The file with the following extensions .DOC, .VBP, .XLS and. FOR are',
    'options':
        'word document, visual basic program, excel and Fortran|word document, visual basic program, excel and Fortran|word document, visual basic package, excel and Fortran|all of the above|none of the above',
    'answer': 'word document, visual basic program, excel and Fortran',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 74,
    'question': 'Ctrl + U will perform what function on a selected text',
    'options': 'select all|underline|paste|cut|none of the above',
    'answer': 'underline',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 75,
    'question': 'The command dir s*.* will',
    'options':
        'display s*.* is not an internal or external command|display an error message|display all dir and files that starts with letter s|display s*.* is a file|display s*.* does not exist',
    'answer': 'display all dir and files that starts with letter s',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 76,
    'question': 'The cls command in DOS',
    'options':
        'shutdown the computer|shutdown the system|display all directory with cls name|restart the program|clear the screen',
    'answer': 'clear the screen',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 77,
    'question':
        'Formatting in Microsoft excel and Microsoft word is the same method',
    'options': 'true|not true|false|b and c are correct|very false',
    'answer': 'true',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 78,
    'question': 'The formula bar in excel displays',
    'options':
        'the data in an active cell|the cell that is selected|a and b is correct|only a is correct|only b is correct',
    'answer': 'a and b is correct',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 79,
    'question': 'Ctrl + Z command will perform what function',
    'options':
        'select all|copy all|Undo the last command|display all zip files|show zip folder',
    'answer': 'Undo the last command',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 80,
    'question': 'Icons are',
    'options':
        'short cuts to programs in the computer|picture commands|picture short cut of Microsoft package in a DOS command|pictorial representations of programs, applications and commands|only d and a are correct',
    'answer':
        'pictorial representations of programs, applications and commands',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 81,
    'question': 'The roller on a PS2 mouse enables the user to',
    'options':
        'scroll up and down|saves 35% of the time spent scrolling a document|zoom in and out a graphic application|a, b and c is correct|only b and c is correct',
    'answer': 'zoom in and out a graphic application',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 82,
    'question': 'Triple click on a mouse selects',
    'options': 'a text|a line or paragraph|a word|all|a letter',
    'answer': 'a line or paragraph',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 83,
    'question': 'To expand the length of a column',
    'options':
        'move the mouse pointer to the line between the columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions|move the mouse pointer to the line between the rows, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions|move the mouse pointer away from the line between the columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions|move the mouse pointer to the line away from columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions|none of the above',
    'answer':
        'move the mouse pointer to the line between the columns, left click holding down and drag to either left or right directions',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 84,
    'question':
        'The network topology in which no central wiring is required is called',
    'options': 'Bus|Ring|Mesh|Star|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Ring',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 85,
    "question":
        "Which of the following networks topology is easier to troubleshoot?",
    "options": "LAN|WAN|MAN|Star|Ring",
    "answer": "Star",
    "answerIndex": 3
  },
  {
    'id': 86,
    'question':
        'The set of rules and procedures governing the transmission between two points in a network is called',
    'options': 'internet|internet card|protocol|topology|none of the above',
    'answer': 'protocol',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 87,
    'question': '_________ is used to connect dissimilar network',
    'options': 'Router|Hub|Switch|Gateways|B-game',
    'answer': 'Gateways',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 88,
    'question': 'The following are the uses of internet except',
    'options': 'E-mail|E-book|Money|E-service|B-game',
    'answer': 'B-game',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 89,
    'question':
        'A method of processing information in which transactions are accumulated and stored until a specific time is called',
    'options':
        'Late processing|Online processing|Batch processing|Immediate processing',
    'answer': 'Batch processing',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 90,
    'question': 'Data processing method include the following except',
    'options': 'ordination|input|process|data capture|storage',
    'answer': 'ordination',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 91,
    'question': 'When 4bits are combined, it is called',
    'options': 'Byte|Word|Nibble|Character|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Nibble',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 92,
    'question': 'A terabyte is equal to',
    'options': '1,024 gigabytes|times gigabyte|megabyte',
    'answer': '1,024 gigabytes',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 93,
    'question': 'The batch processing and online processing fall under',
    'options':
        'Electronic method|Manual method|Mechanical method|All of the above|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Electronic method',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 94,
    'question': 'The DOS command tine is also called the',
    'options': 'window|Internet command|command prompt|B & C|none of the above',
    'answer': 'command prompt',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 95,
    'question': 'The command used to copy files and directing trees is called',
    'options': 'V copy|copy|Copy con|none of the above',
    'answer': 'copy',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 96,
    'question': 'Files deleted from flash goes into the',
    'options': 'Recycle bin|my document|my computer|A & B|none of the above',
    'answer': 'none of the above',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 97,
    'question':
        'Every time a window is opened, a button representing it appears on the',
    'options': 'start button|task bar|title bar|desktop|all of the above',
    'answer': 'task bar',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 98,
    'question': 'The task bar contains start button and _____ area',
    'options': 'Blue|Notification|Black|White|All of the above',
    'answer': 'Notification',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 99,
    'question':
        'To view properties for the selected item, the following combinations of keys are used',
    'options': 'Ctrl + z|Alt + Enter|F8+ A|none of the above',
    'answer': 'Alt + Enter',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 100,
    'question':
        'A step by step method that is used to solve a problem is called',
    'options': 'Algorithm|Flowchart|Program|Software|All',
    'answer': 'Algorithm',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 101,
    'question': 'Assembly language is _________ language',
    'options':
        '1st generation|2nd generation|3rd generation|4th generation|All of the above',
    'answer': '2nd generation',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 102,
    'question':
        'Instructions in first generation language are given using _____',
    'options':
        'Mnemonics|binary numbers|natural expressions|a & b|none of the above',
    'answer': 'binary numbers',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 103,
    'question':
        'Ability of the operating system to perform several tasks parallel is called ____',
    'options':
        'Concurrence|Multitasking|Mono programming|None of the above|All of the above',
    'answer': 'Concurrence',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 104,
    'question': 'The temporary storage in the computer’s memory is called',
    'options': 'Cache|Primary memory|Buffer|Flash|All',
    'answer': 'Buffer',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 105,
    'question':
        'To store the current line for further editing _________ key is used',
    'options': 'Fl|F2|F8|F2|F3',
    'answer': 'F3',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 106,
    'question': 'All are examples of internal DOS commands except',
    'options': 'TYPE|VOL|DIR|COPY|all of the above|none of the above',
    'answer': 'COPY',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 107,
    'question': 'The extension name for general data files is',
    'options': 'BAT|DCC|DAT|GDF|none of the above',
    'answer': 'DAT',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 108,
    'question': 'In a dialogue box _____ provides a list of toggle options',
    'options': 'Drop-down lists boxes|Check boxes|Option button|A&B|None',
    'answer': 'Check boxes',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 109,
    'question': 'Every location in the computer memory has___________',
    'options':
        'Unique address|general address|primary address|secondary address|no address',
    'answer': 'Unique address',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 110,
    'question': 'The following are parts of window except',
    'options': 'menu bar|tool bar|scroll bar|recycle bin|all of the above',
    'answer': 'all of the above',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 111,
    'question':
        'The movement of full or part of document from one space to another leaving the original copy is called',
    'options': 'cutting|copying|pasting|editing|all of the above',
    'answer': 'copying',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 112,
    'question':
        'The screen of Microsoft word is made up of the following except',
    'options': 'title bar|menu bar|standard toolbar|formatting toolbar|icon',
    'answer': 'icon',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 113,
    'question': 'The keyboard shortcut for replace is _____',
    'options': 'Ctrl + F|Ctrl + G|Ctrl + H|All of the above|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Ctrl + H',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 114,
    'question': 'Groups of cells are called _____',
    'options': 'formula addresses|range|excel|A & B|none of the above',
    'answer': 'range',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 115,
    'question': 'The smallest unit of a database is called',
    'options': 'character|field|records|DBMS|none of the above',
    'answer': 'character',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 116,
    'question': 'The way data is stored in a database is called_____________',
    'options': 'Logical view|Physical view|Schema|Subschema|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Physical view',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 117,
    'question': 'The first generation computers were generally very',
    'options': 'good|unreliable|reliable|understandable|none',
    'answer': 'unreliable',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 118,
    'question':
        'An integrated package comprising of several programs is called',
    'options': 'Microsoft word|Windows|Icon|DOS|None',
    'answer': 'Windows',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 119,
    'question':
        'The first and introductory screen of windows is called the_____',
    'options': 'wall paper|screensaver|desktop|mouse|all',
    'answer': 'desktop',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 120,
    'question':
        'The first and introductory screen of windows is called the_____',
    'options': 'wallpaper|screensaver|desktop|mouse|all',
    'answer': 'desktop',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 121,
    'question': 'To prompt to cell address to be jumped to in Excel, press',
    'options': 'F1|F2|F4|F6|none of the above',
    'answer': 'F5',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 122,
    'question': 'The arrangement of data in the computer memory is called',
    'options':
        'data processing|data capture|data integrity|data structure|none of the above',
    'answer': 'data structure',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 123,
    'question': 'Which of the following is true about data?',
    'options':
        'Data are processed facts|Data are information|Data are unprocessed|Information processed to give data|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Data are unprocessed',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 124,
    'question': 'The database offers the following capabilities except',
    'options':
        'inserting data|retrieving data|updating data|overwriting data|deleting data',
    'answer': 'overwriting data',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 125,
    'question': 'An operating system is also called ____________',
    'options': 'Directory|Processor|Supervisor|File|none of the above',
    'answer': 'Supervisor',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 126,
    'question': 'One of these is not a first-generation computer',
    'options': 'ENIAC|ABC|IBM 300|UNIVAC|Mark I',
    'answer': 'IBM 300',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 127,
    'question': 'One of the following is not necessary in LAN',
    'options': 'Modem|Adapter card|Cable|45|Hub',
    'answer': 'Modem',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 128,
    'question':
        'A secondary memory with storage of 10.2MB is equivalent to how many characters',
    'options': '102000|10200000|102000000|1020000000|11200000',
    'answer': '10200000',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 129,
    'question':
        'Which of the following operating system is suitable for networking',
    'options':
        'Windows 31|Windows 95|Windows NT|Windows 2000|Disk Operating System',
    'answer': 'Windows NT',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 130,
    'question':
        'The following are examples of database management systems except',
    'options': 'oracle|MS Excel|super base 2|MS ACCESS|Mysol',
    'answer': 'MS Excel',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 131,
    'question': 'Windows is _________',
    'options':
        'not an operating system|behaves like an operating system|command driven|part of an operating system|none of the above',
    'answer': 'none of the above',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 132,
    'question': 'One of the following is not harmful to the computer',
    'options': 'spyware|virus|PO-culling|Worm|Trojan',
    'answer': 'PO-culling',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 133,
    'question': 'Which of the following is not a LAN Topology',
    'options': 'Bus|Star|door-to-door|Ring|Mesh',
    'answer': 'door-to-door',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 134,
    'question': 'One of the following is not necessary in LAN',
    'options': 'Modem|Adapter card|cable|RJ 45|Hub',
    'answer': 'Modem',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 135,
    'question': 'A major distinction between LAN and WAN is ___________',
    'options': 'distance apart|communication|Integrity|modem|all of the above',
    'answer': 'all of the above',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 136,
    'question': 'One of these is not a Presentation Graphics Software',
    'options': 'Freelance|Excel|Power Point|Corel Draw|none',
    'answer': 'Excel',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 137,
    'question':
        'Which of the following factors is responsible for the rise of the Internet’s popularity',
    'options':
        'the World Wide Web|the elimination of barriers to commercial activity on the internet|online service providers|A and B above|all',
    'answer': 'all',
    'answerIndex': 4
  },
  {
    'id': 138,
    'question':
        'The FORMAT command in addition to preparing the disk for use also',
    'options':
        'adds information to the disk|deletes every content of the disk|arrange all files in the in order|compresses the content of the disk|none of the above',
    'answer': 'deletes every content of the disk',
    'answerIndex': 1
  },
  {
    'id': 139,
    'question': 'The function of the command DIR EXE is to',
    'options':
        'write all files to the disk|display every file in the disk|display only file with extension|display files not having extension.EXE|none of the above',
    'answer': 'display only file with extension',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 140,
    'question': 'One of the following enhances windows operations',
    'options': 'Keyboard|Light pen|Mouse|Joystick|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Mouse',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 141,
    'question':
        'In windows application the background of the desktop is called',
    'options': 'title bar|stack bar|wall paper|screen saver|none',
    'answer': 'wall paper',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 142,
    'question': 'The earliest forerunner of modern digital computer is',
    'options': 'Abacus|Main|Desktop|Laptop|IBM',
    'answer': 'Abacus',
    'answerIndex': 0
  },
  {
    'id': 143,
    'question': 'The first electronic known computer is called',
    'options': 'Punch card|Digital computer|ENIAC|IBM|None of the above',
    'answer': 'ENIAC',
    'answerIndex': 2
  },
  {
    'id': 144,
    'question': 'The second-generation operating system supported',
    'options':
        'single processing|batch processing|multi programmed system|my document|none of a, b, C',
    'answer': 'multi programmed system',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 145,
    'question': 'A manager of a database is called',
    'options': 'BDA|DBMA|DBP|Data base manager|none of a,b,c or d',
    'answer': 'Data base manager',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 146,
    'question': 'A modem is normally required in',
    'options': 'PAN|LAN|multiplexer|Wide area Network|none of the above',
    'answer': 'Wide area Network',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 147,
    'question':
        'The circuit devices that dominated first generation computers is called',
    'options':
        'Diode|Integrated Circuit|Translator|Vacuum tubes|None of the above',
    'answer': 'Vacuum tubes',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 148,
    'question': 'The third generation computers were built using',
    'options': 'SSI circuit|MSI circuit|LSI circuit|VLSI circuits|none',
    'answer': 'LSI circuit',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 149,
    'question':
        'A device that enables computer user to save work after a power failure is',
    'options': 'modern|scanner|stabilizer|UPS|none of the above',
    'answer': 'UPS',
    'answerIndex': 3
  },
  {
    'id': 150,
    'question':
        'Data and program instructions which are being processed by the computer are held in',
    'options': 'hard disk|control unit|main memory|ALU|none of the above',
    'answer': 'main memory',
    'answerIndex': 2
  }
];
